Zachary Branum

(405)248-2255

9801 S Harrah Rd, Newalla, OK 74857

zbranum@gmail.com

Professional Profile

I have work in a technical environment for 12 years, working on communication systems, networking, computer repair, camera installation, server setups. I have been a Manager for 8 years in charge of budgeting, employee interviews, disciplinary action, and scheduling.

- Scheduling
- Maintaining a budget
- Interviewing
- Network troubleshooting
- Project Management
- Surveillance camera installation

- Policy writing
- Computer troubleshooting
- Problem Solving
- Knowledge of Microsoft Office Suites
- Access Control Installation and maintenance

Professional Experience

SemGas, Cherokee, OK March 2017 - Present I&E Technician I

Responsibilities:

- Troubleshooting of instrumentation and electrical systems
- Construction of Compressor Stations
- Build and install PLC/HMI panels
- Self-Scheduling
- Manage Contractors
- Training new I&E Technicians
- Instrument Calibration
- PLC and HMI programming

Kickapoo Tribe of Oklahoma, Mcloud, OK October 2012 – March 2017

Surveillance Manager / Gaming Systems Manager

Achievements:

- Oklahoma City Regulating Gaming Technology Training Course NIGC
- Oklahoma City Regional Training Course NIGC

Responsibilities:

- Employee Scheduling
- Maintaining a Budget
- Maintenance of all surveillance equipment
- Installation of cameras, command centers, and servers
- Drafting surveillance Policies
- Supervise and train Surveillance Operators
- Act as oversight for management or customers
- Monitor establishment activities to ensure adherence to all state gaming regulations and company policies and procedures

GO CS Inc., Shawnee, OK July 2008 – August 2012

Project Manager

Achievements:

- EAS Certified Alarm Technician Level 1
- Webvision Certification Honeywell Webvision Training
- Panasonic I-Pro Certified Technical Specialists
- Oklahoma Alarm and Locksmith License CCTV Technician, Electronic Access Control Technician (Expired)

Responsibilities:

- Manage financial records
- Plan and implement Terminal Servers
- Plan and implement Domain Servers (AD, DHCP, DNS)
- Plan and implement Access Control and Surveillance systems for casinos
- Budget for all projects
- Inventory control for all projects
- Review employee timesheets
- Manage install teams and employee's schedules

Nielsen Media Research, New York, NY June 2007 – June 2008

Field Representative

Achievements:

- Certificate of Completion Nielsen Media Research Field Training School
- Top Gun Award Achieving a 97% or Higher GPA
- Adapt Improve Overcome Award

Responsibilities:

- Installation of data collection equipment
- Manage personal work schedule
- Wireless network configuration
- Perform preventive maintenance

Citizen Potawatomi Nation, Shawnee, OK May 2006 – June 2008

Network Engineer

Achievements:

A+ Certified Professional

Responsibilities:

- Installation and maintenance of casino production devices
- Upgraded gaming network infrastructure for new system
- Termination of Cat3, Cat5, Cat5e, and Cat6 cable

Education

Gordon Cooper Technology Center, Shawnee, Ok

Certificate of Completion – Network Systems Technology May 2006

McIoud High School, Shawnee, Ok **High School Diploma** May 2006

References

References are available upon request.